# Manish Kumar Verma

Vill. -Gunj, Po. -Kishangarh-Bass,Alwar (Rajasthan) ■ Contact- 08851349832
mkerma3131989@gmail.com ■ www.linkedin.com/in/manish-verma-65b3a9109

## **Technical Support Engineer**

Proven Success in Systems Optimization and Strategic IT Solutions **Multi-certified (RHCE,RHCSA,DCA) support engineer** with strong experience managing server infrastructures and data-center operations across Unix, Linux, and Windows platforms. Effectively plan, install, configure and optimize IT infrastructures to achieve high availability and performance.

**Proven ability to create and deliver solutions tied to business growth,** organizational development and systems/network optimization. Skilled problem identifier and troubleshooter comfortable managing systems, projects and teams in a range of IT environments.

## IT SKILLS

- > Apache, Nginx
- Active Directory
- Workflow Planning

- Cpanel, Plesk
- Systems Installation, Configuration
- ServiceNow

- ➤ Share Drive/Backup
- ➤ NOS Patches & Updates
- Training & Mentoring

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### TECHNIP GLOBAL BUSINESS SERVICES PRIVATE LIMITED, NOIDA ■ 2017 to Present

**System Engineer/Linux** (Aug 2017 to Present)

Hired as a full-time systems engineer following initial consulting role to manage and maintain a 60+ mixed server environment (Windows/Linux), ensuring 99.9% or better uptime. Evaluate, monitor and enhance IT infrastructure with an emphasis on availability, reliability, scalability, security, data confidentiality and system integrity.

## **Key Contributions:**

- Installed and configured all the Linux servers in the network per specifications of clients...
- ➤ Monitored the servers and Linux scripts regularly and performed troubleshooting steps Tested and installed the latest software on server for end-users.
- Attended calls related to customer queries and complaints, offered solutions.
- Performed routine checks on the Linux servers of the firm.
- ➤ Perform Active Directory Services administration & management to include access provide & revoke & routine maintenance.
- Working on escalated tickets & maintaining SLA for enhancement requests are as per ServiceNow
- Monitor network communication by Linux Essential Tools Like (Linuxconf, Cockpit, Puppet)
- Updating UNIX OS patches, and managing server deployment
- Set up and administer user and groups accounts, setting permissions for users.

# MANISH KUAMR VERMA

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **EXTRAMARKS EDUCATION PVT. LTD, JAIPUR** ■ Sep2015 to Aug 2017 **IT Executive**

Consulted with client companies to evaluate, recommend and deploy Web-based and network solutions. Provided strategic planning and project leadership over systems migration, configuration, administration, upgrades and troubleshooting initiatives.

#### **Key Contributions:**

- Installation of Linux Distribution RHEL, CentOS, Ubuntu/Debian, Linux Mint etc.
- > Installation & configuration of web hosting control panels like Cpanel, Plesk, DirectAdmin.
- Maintain in-house FTP and WEB Server, IIS, Print and File servers.
- Maintaining Mail Servers, Web Servers, DNS Servers etc.
- Managing the backup and recovery solutions.
- ➤ Handling Live Chats and tickets with support dept. at Level1-Level4.
- ➤ Also handled billing and sales related queries.

#### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

- Jaipur National University, Jaipur Master of Computer Applications (MCA)
- Eastern Institute for Integrated Learning in Management, Sikkim **Bachelor in Computer Application (BCA)**
- RHCSA (Redhat Certified System Administrator) From Linux World, Jaipur
- RHCE (Red Hat Certified Engineer) from IIHT Ltd. Nehru Place, Jaipur
- Red Hat SELinux Policy Administration From Network Nuts, Delhi
- Red Hat Services and Authentication Certificate of Expertise From Network Nuts, Delhi
- DCA (Diploma in computer applications) from Shri Ram Computer Edu, Chiittorgarh

	PERSONAL DETAILS	
Date of Birth:	31 March 1989	
Father's Name:	Mr. Kailash Chand Verma	
Gender:	Male	
Hobbies:	Playing sports indoor and outdoor.	
Local Address:	New Ashok Nagar, Delhi	
	DECLARATION — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — — —	

I hereby declare that the above information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

DATE: (Manish Kumar Verma)